Chude Steve Nnamdi

I am a proactive, smart, driven software engineer with 5 years of development experience. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. I am a proficient React, Next.Js, Angular.Js, React Native, JavaScript and TypeScript developer. Softwares i have built includes Fintech Payment Website, Health Tech solution, logistics web app, etc. I have great communication skills, problem solving, decision making and I am a team player.

Alhaji Arije's compound, off Zimest avenue, Greenville Estate. Ajah Badore, Lagos State.

+2348089147905

Email: stevechude@gmail.com
Github: https://github.com/stevechude
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/st

eve-chude-6734a7191/

website: https://steve-chude.vercel.app/

EXPERIENCE

Tezza Business Solution, Lagos — Frontend Developer (Contract)

OCTOBER 2023 - MARCH 2024

- Building several web applications, including a Test Data management app that a telecom company can use in testing their products before distribution.
- Team Lead of the development team.
- Working with Next Js Framework and Tailwind CSS.
- Optimizing the app and improving its performance.
- API Integration with the backend server built with Node.Js.

HuiosPay Limited, Abuja — Frontend Developer (Remote)

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

- Building the Payslate web app which is a multipurpose payment platform for customers to sign up on and make easy payments for eg: (school fees, rent, subscriptions, etc).
- Working with Next Js Framework and Tailwind CSS.
- API Integration with the backend server to implement all functionalities as relates to the Payslate website.

Talosmart Limited, Lagos – NextJS Developer (Contract)

APRIL 2023 - August 2023

- Member of a team building the Switch Hive website, where users can make mobile top-ups, buy gift cards and pay bills with crypto.
- Built the Blog post section
- Built the Gift Cards flow, where users can view the info on a selected card and add to their cart for purchase.
- Built the modal for Sign up and Login.
- Consuming API endpoints built with NodeJs and Web3

Bottleking Nigeria Ltd, Lagos — Fullstack Developer (Hybrid)

AUGUST 2021 - DECEMBER 2022

- Responsible for implementing the new UI designs for the company's e-commerce website with React js and consumed all backend API's built in Node js.
- Built a new landing page and a new user authentication pages including (sign up, login, logout, email verification pages) and added timed pop ups for newsletter sign up, blogs and company give-aways, all mobile responsive.
- Maintained the old website built in Next js and installed google ad tracking and conversion codes for google analytics.

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React js
- Next js
- Angular
- RxJs
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Nodejs
- Jira
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven Development.
- Agile Methodologies.

CERTIFICATIONS

• SCRUM Fundamentals Certified

PROJECTS

PAYSLATE APP:

A modern payment solution app that has 2 user journeys (Organization & Users). A company can open a payslate account to easily receive payments from their customers, while an individual can open a payslate account to easily connect with multiple organizations registered on the platform and make payments to them.

Technologies Used - Next Js, Tailwind, Javascript, Redux.

Link - https://www.payslate.com.ng/

SWITCH HIVE WEBSITE:

A platform where users can spend crypto in a fast and easy way while earning points by referrals. Make mobile top-ups, buy gift cards and pay bills with crypto for over 1000 products globally.

Technologies Used - Next Js, TailwindCSS, Vercel, Node.js, Web3.

Link -https://switchive.com/

GIFT CARD LANDING PAGE:

A fully responsive landing page of a GiftCard website from Figma Design, built and styled in 6 days with Next Js and TailwindCSS. Used GSAP library for animations.

Technologies Used - Next Js, TailwindCSS, GSAP, Vercel.

Link - https://gift-card-phi.vercel.app/

NextJS BLOG WEBSITE:

A beautiful blog website built with Next Js and hosted on Vercel. With server side rendering of a static database API file and dynamic page rendering of each blog article. Styled with tailwind Css.

Technologies Used - Next Js, tailwind CSS, Vercel.

Link - https://blog-by-steve.vercel.app/

CRYPTOBASE WEBSITE:

A responsive crypto website fetched from coingecko's api as third-party, built with react js and styled with tailwind css, with an addition of a firebase backend with full user authentications and route protections.

Technologies Used - React Js, tailwind CSS, Firebase, Coingecko API.

Link: https://cryptobase-website.netlify.app/

FOODMINE ANGULAR APP (IN PROGRESS):

A foodmine website built with angular, it represents a food commerce app with the

following features (view all available foods, view foods by categories, click on a particular food, add food to cart, view cart page with all foods added to cart). It is still missing an API server for user authentication (sign up and login, payment and checkout page) though, but it is an awesome representation of a food-commerce web application.

Technologies Used - Angular 14, CSS, NodeJS.

Link - https://foodmine-app.vercel.app/

BOTTLEKING WEBSITE (Staging environment):

A responsive website design deployed for testing on netlify.

Technologies Used - React js, CSS, Node js(backend)

Link: https://bottleking.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

Federal University Of Technology Owerri — B.eng

OCTOBER 2012 - FEBRUARY 2017

Second Class - Bachelor of Engineering degree in Mechanical Engineering From **FUTO**, Nigeria.